I’ve always wanted a family.
I’ve always felt that urge, deep inside me.
But for this, I knew migration was the only way.
The summers in Ghana were harsh, humid, thousands of species were competing for the little food that was left.
And how could I stand a chance, me, a 14g bird, against the turacos, the pelicans, the parrots.
They were larger, faster, more powerful than us, cleverer against the predators.
If I wanted a family, if I ever wanted to have something to offer them, then I had to go.
Staying was looking at the past. Leaving was about the future.
I had heard so many stories about the great British summers.
The warm, balmy air, the late sunsets, the evergreen forests with plenty of opportunities to eat and find a mate.
My friends and I used to fantasise about it, we asked our mothers and aunts to tell us all about their own journeys, how they met our fathers, our uncles.
It all felt so romantic, something worth flying across two continents for.
The power of love. We were young birds, we all wanted it.
No matter the risks, the cold, the exhaustion, the hunger, we knew nature was calling us.
It was a dream, they were sirens too powerful to escape.
The greater the dangers, the greater the rewards, we thought.
It was fate. It was destiny.
At last, the day of departure came: there were eighty of us in our flock, eighty young lovers ready to take Europe by storm.
We gathered on the branches of a mahogany tree.
For once, none of us talked. We just watched the sun rise in silence, absorbing the smells, the colours, the sounds of our homeland.
And then, as one body, we all opened our wings and took over the blue open sky.